I heard something very important that
I've been thinking for a very long time
and I put it into into writing yesterday
just briefly on no start and
explain it to Marx and and now I'm
starting to think it's it's an important
thing because this could be the key of
uh of a better future this this argument
could be summarized by either leaving
Friedman's Vision
he wrote about in the future in perfect
or The Sovereign individualized Vision
but they wrote in
1998 ish
so
both of both of these
are thinking about the same idea
which is that there are there are two
things in this world
meet space
and
cyberspace
so
as time is passing
the relevancy of meat space will go down
and the relevance of cyberspace will go
up
this is something we can we can feel
uh because we can look at the past and
this is happening because spend more
time on need space than cyberspace
so how long is these plans that are
continual I don't know
but
it's nothing considerable that
meat space is gonna be almost irrelevant
at one point and cyberspace is going to
be the irrelevant thing to to focus on
so that's that's one thing now
there is a problem in this verb
which is the management of violence
and the thesis of sovereign individuals
that we can
analyze violence
um and try to predict where it's going
and
you might be tempted to analyze violence
in terms of individual
or groups of the individuals
who has power here
currently
it is it is government
who are monopolizing on most of the
powers and that there are individuals
[Music]
who has less and less Powers now there's
another distinction in between the
powers because powers can be
defensive mainly or you know position or
fancy
[Music]
um think about
nuclear compounds or organs they are
mainly offensive but only BTC stands
like encryption Anonymous communication
surround means money they are mainly the
fancy they are defending the individuals
or groups but but this is not not one
size pizza so it could be defensive and
offensive at the same time in different
contexts so so so this is just a rough
estimation
um now individuals
increasing the defense if powers of the
individuals against the groups should be
the lower because groups right now hold
like a monopoly on power
and it would be better to
to get some
some power back from the groups those
are monopolizing the power for us now it
must be noted that there is going to be
a side effect of of that which is that
smaller individuals will also be able to
to make to do suffering into the world
in more degrees as technology
is empowering the individuals so small
and organized crime like that's going to
rise and the largest organized crime
like governments are going to go down
um in terms of power or
one of our market share of violence so
so this is the context to the idea of
what I'm going to talk about now
the cheese
that
concerning cyberspace
can be built
an economy
there
the trade
is
unobservable
because if the groups have monopolyon
violence in need space what we could do
is that to make it so that in cyberspace
they do not they do not see
going on the economy because it's an
unseen economy eventually this is the
economy that is going to matter because
that's side versus but cyberspace is
going to be the space what is going to
matter in the future you don't know how
how long it's gonna take but the trends
are pretty clear so the question is how
do we build a cyber space economy and
unobservable cyber space economy for
that
let's analyze trade so what is the trade
happens between two parties
to people or groups of individuals
usually one of the one of the party
has a thing uh let's call it good or
service that it's offering
and the other party usually has an
obstruction of volume and that's called
money
[Music]
and they are
exchanging these things for money to
good that's a trade okay now the trick
here is it's happening in a context
so there is although money mediates the
exchange of goods their
is something that mediates the entire
trade and that is the communication in
between the parties
[Music]
foreign
someone creates some volume good it
exchanges needs for some abstract
agreement of value and
they are communicating how this thing
should be happening now what does it
mean
it's in order to make this straight this
economy
unobservable they must build all three
consequences of a trade make them
unobservable so communication money and
Technology
let's start with the good
the sink here is that this has a huge
variety of things you can be selling
things and posts and send it physically
you can be also selling a service where
everyone has to be in the same place and
you get a massage or you can be sending
another kind of service cloud computing
um which doesn't require any kind of
physical presence but it would require
in order to make it unobservable it
would require some kind of technical
solution for that all of these these
Goods these are very variety
that's what's been exchanged on the
marketplace every every one of these
require or or benefit
from having a unique approach of
exchanging that builds and observably so
what are these tools then these are the
business opportunities
of all the young upcoming cyber and
Cipher punks but you know that let's
change it is good we also need
uncertainty also needs to make
communication and money an observable on
top of it otherwise it wouldn't work
let's say there was some great idea
because
it was a decentralized market space and
the thing was there that they didn't
have Anonymous communication Anonymous
money
accessible or or the solutions were not
good enough for them I mean assuming
means money that's very expensive and
very slow I mean sure you can build
certain kind of goods or services but
but we we want the money to be as good
as any other money is
and to be an observable so an and that's
when we can get to the cycle company now
we have to build it on means one million
dollars Communications and it would
actually be very handy if a developer
any developer would want to do some some
crazy crazy words changing idea in the
new and observable Cipher pump economy
um communication and money so this
should be because this is a constant
part of every single airplane these
private visits should be already
provided in a library for example
okay
so that's what we need to do first we
have to build Anonymous communication
and unknownings money in order and power
Cypher punks who Wanna Build specific
services for specific things and have an
unobservable cyberpunk economy what
these results do is that the trades are
not going to be observed anymore via
[Music]
evil selfie
who actually has meat space violence
Monopoly against
the parties who are transacting if we
cut this off if they she cannot see
what's happening then
we will have an economy that doesn't
is not limited by the violence
organizations of each space